Guide to the Papers on the Allen Ginsberg bibliography,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
George Dowden Papers on the Allen Ginsberg Bibliography,
1966-1971
Dowden, George
ca. 3,000 (4 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078710
History
Scope and Content
Correspondence, working notes, and drafts used by Dowden (b. ca. 1933) in compiling his work A Bibliography of Works by Allen Ginsberg. Dowden corresponded with many writers, publishers, editors, and libraries in compiling a comprehensive bibliography of Allen Ginsberg's poetry and prose, published before 1 July 1967. Among the correspondents are Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Allen Ginsberg, John Clellon Holmes, Robert La Vigne, Gerard Malanga, Fernanda Pivano, and Gary Snyder.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 3 series:
Cataloged Material
Series II: Arranged Correspondence
Series III: A Bibliography of Works by Allen Ginsberg
Subjects
Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.; Holmes, John Clellon, 1926-1988.; Lavigne, Robert.; Malanga, Gerard.; Pivano, Fernanda.; Snyder, Gary.; Bohemianism--United States.; Poets, American--20th century.; American literature--20th century.; American literature--20th century--Bibliography.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-4. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1959 M-59
- Series I: Cataloged Material
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence
    Cataloged correspondence and manuscripts are interfiled
    - Allen, Donald M. To George Dowden, San Francisco, 8 May 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copy of 1 related letter]
    - Berke, Joseph H. To George Dowden, London, 19 Aug 1969, (3 pages a.l.s. (p. 3 typewritten) (Box 1)
      [With copies of 2 related letters]
    - Berke, Joseph H. To George Dowden, London, 30 Sept 1969, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copy of reply]
    - Berke, Joseph H. To George Dowden, London, [Oct 1969], (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Blackburn, Paul To George Dowden, New York, 31 May [1967], (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Cantwell, Robert To George Dowden, New York, 7 Oct 1967, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Chamberlain, Wynn To George Dowden, [New York], 22 Sept 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, [San Francisco], [March 1966], (1 page a.l. (his notes written on GD's letter) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 2 March 1966, (1 page t.l.s. (with copy of related letter bearing LF's notes) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, [June 1966], (1 p.c.s. (with copy of related letter) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 25 Aug 1966, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 7 Sept 1966, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 25 April 1967, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Blackburn, Paul To George Dowden, New York, 31 May [1967], (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 12 [i.e., 11] May 1967, (1 p.c.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 1 June 1967, (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, [8 June 1967], (1 p.c.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With GD's related notes, 4 pages]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 20 June 1967, (1 p.c.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 7 July 1967, (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copies of 3 related letters]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, [San Francisco], [Dec 1967], (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [Written on GD's letter; with carbon copy]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 18 Jan 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copies of 2 related letters & notes]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To Marthe Whitcomb Rexroth (Mrs. Kenneth), San Francisco, [May 1969], (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 8 May 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 8 May 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, [June 1969], (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, [Aug 1969], (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copy of reply & related letter bearing LF's notes, 3 pages]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 5 Sept 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 15 Sept 1969, (1 page t.l.s., 3 related letters, ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, [San Francisco], 6 Nov 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copy of reply & receipt]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 2 Dec 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 12 Jan 1970, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copies of 2 replies]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 23 Feb 1970, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, [ca. March 1970], (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With 6 related letters & list]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 5 July 1970, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 11 Aug 1970, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, [ca. 20 Aug 1970], (4 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [Pages 2-4 written on GD's list of questions; With copy of reply]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 21 Dec 1970, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copies of 6 related letters]
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To George Dowden, San Francisco, 24 March 1971, (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [New York], [ca. March 1967], (2 pages a.l., ) (Box 1)
      [Notes written on GD's letter; With copies of 3 related letters]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, London, 5 Aug 1967, (1 telegram, ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [London], 16 Aug [1967], (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With envelope & copy of reply]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [London], [18 Aug 1967], (1 a.n.s. (on envelope) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, Milan, 11 Nov 1967, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With envelope & copies of 3 related letters]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, London, 28 Nov 1967, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [New York], [25 Jan 1968], (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, New York, 28 March 1968, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [New York], 29 April 1968, (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, New York, 28 May 1968, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [New York], 20 June 1968, (1 page a.l., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [New York], 18 Oct 1968, (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With questionnaire, 9 pages, filled in by AG & copy of related letter]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [New York], 27 Jan 1968, (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copy of related letter]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [New York], [Jan 1969], (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [Written on related letter; With copy of reply & questionnaire, 12 pages]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, Cherry Valley, NY, 10 March 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With 11 page questionnaire filled in by AG & copy of related letter]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, Cherry Valley, NY, 15 April 1969, (1 p.c.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [Cherry Valley, NY], [Oct 1969], (7 pages a.l., ) (Box 1)
      [5 pages written on lettter from GD; With copies of 2 related letters]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, Cherry Valley, NY, 7 July 1969, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With 2 questionnaires filled in by AG; With copies of 3 related letters]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [Cherry Valley, NY], [Sept 1969], (3 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [Written on related letter; With copy of letter]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [Cherry Valley, NY], [10 Dec 1969], (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copies of 2 related letters & bank check]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, Cherry Valley, NY, [Jan 1970], (8 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [4 pages in AG's hand; with copy of reply]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [Cherry Valley, NY], 7 [i.e. 6] Feb 1970, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, Cherry Valley, NY, 11 Feb 1970, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [Cherry Valley, NY], 19 Feb 1970, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copies of 4 related letters & customs form]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [Cherry Valley, NY], 23 May 1970, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copy of reply & AG's notes on Mantras, 2 pages]
    - Ginsberg, Allen To George Dowden, [Cherry Valley, NY], 27 Jan [i.e. Feb] 1971, (1 p.c.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 15 Oct 1966, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 26 Oct 1966, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With clipping & carbon copy of reply]
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, [ca. April 1967], (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With carbon copy of reply]
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 12 May 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [2 poems enclosed; With copy of reply]
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 21 Dec 1967, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 12 March 1968, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 31 May 1968, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, [June 1968], (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 14 June 1968, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With carbon copies of 2 related letters]
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 22 Aug 1969, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 4 Sept 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 3 Dec 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis To George Dowden, Paterson, NJ, 5 Dec 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, Buenos Aires, 23 March 1966, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, [Buenos Aires], 24 June 1966, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, [Buenos Aires], 30 January 1967, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, [Buenos Aires], [1 Feb 1967], (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, [Buenos Aires], 18 May 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, Buenos Aires, 7 June 1967, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, Buenos Aires, 31 Aug 1967, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, [Buenos Aires], [ca. Oct 1967], (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Grinberg, Miguel To George Dowden, [Buenos Aires], 20 Nov 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Harding, Gunnar To George Dowden, Stockholm, 30 Aug 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With enclosed bibliography & copies of 2 related letters]
    - Harding, Gunnar To George Dowden, Stockholm, 1 Nov 1967, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Harding, Gunnar To George Dowden, Stockholm, 11 Nov 1967, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Harding, Gunnar To George Dowden, Iowa City, IA, 14 March 1969, (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Holmes, John Clellon To George Dowden, Old Saybrook, CT, 17 Aug 1967, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Holmes, John Clellon To George Dowden, [London], [Oct 1967], (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Holmes, John Clellon To George Dowden, Old Saybrook, CT, 23 Jan 1967 [i.e., 1968], (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Holmes, John Clellon To George Dowden, Old Saybrook, CT, 18 Sept 1968, (2 pages t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Kupferberg, Tuli To George Dowden, New York, 29 June 1964, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With copies of 4 related letters]
    - Laughlin, James To George Dowden, New York, 28 June 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Laughlin, James To George Dowden, New York, 5 Oct 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Laughlin, James To George Dowden, New York, 18 Oct 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - La Vigne, Robert To George Dowden, Bennington, VT, [ca. Nov 1967], (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - La Vigne, Robert To George Dowden, San Francisco, 20 Jan 1968, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Label, Jean-Jacques To George Dowden, [Paris], [23 June 1966], (1 p.c.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Malanga, Gerard To George Dowden, New York, 6 July 1966, (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Malanga, Gerard To George Dowden, [New York], [Aug 1967], (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [Written on related letter; With copies of 3 related letters]
    - Pivano, Fernanda Sottsass To George Dowden, Milan, 22 June 1966, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Pivano, Fernanda Sottsass To George Dowden, Milan, 8 Sept 1966, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Pivano, Fernanda Sottsass To George Dowden, Milan, 30 Oct 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Pivano, Fernanda Sottsass To George Dowden, [Milan], 14 Dec 1967, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Pivano, Fernanda Sottsass To George Dowden, Milan, [Sept 1969], (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Pivano, Fernanda Sottsass To George Dowden, Milan, 21 Oct 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Rexroth, Martha Whitcomb (Mrs. Kenneth) To Lawrence Ferlinghetti, [San Francisco], [May 1969], (1 page a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [For this item See Ferlinghetti, Lawrence. To George Dowden, [May 1969].]
    - Snyder, Gary To George Dowden, [Kyoto], 17 Sept [1967], (2 pages a.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With envelope &amp copy of related letter]
    - Snyder, Gary To George Dowden, San Francisco, [June 1969], (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
    - Snyder, Gary To George Dowden, Mill Valley, CA, 26 Oct 1969, (1 page t.l.s., ) (Box 1)
      [With envelope &amp copies of 2 related letters]
  - Subseries I.2: Manuscripts
    - Dowden, George [autobiographical data], [Brighton, UK], [26 May 1970], (1 page t.ms., ) (Box 1)
      [With copy of 2 related letters]
    - Dowden, George [A bibliography of works by Allen Ginsberg] - preface, [Brighton, UK], 23 Nov 1969, (9 pages a.ms.s. (first draft) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George [A bibliography of works by Allen Ginsberg] - preface, Brighton, UK, 23 Nov 1969, (9 pages t.ms. (second draft; with many changes in the author's hand) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George [A bibliography of works by Allen Ginsberg] - preface, Brighton, UK, 23 Nov 1969, (9 pages a.ms. (third draft; notes on proof of preface) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George [A bibliography of works by Allen Ginsberg] - preface, Brighton, [UK], 10 Jan 1971, (11 pages t.ms. (fourth draft; with corrections in the author's hand) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George [A bibliography of works by Allen Ginsberg] - preface, Brighton, [UK], 14 March 1971, (5 pages a.ms.s. (fifth draft) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George [A bibliography of works by Allen Ginsberg] - preface, Brighton, [UK], 14 March 1971, (6 pages t.ms. (sixth draft; with many changes in the author's hand) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George [A bibliography of works by Allen Ginsberg] - preface, Brighton, [UK], 14 March 1971, (5 pages t.ms. (seventh draft; with changes in the author's hand) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George [A bibliography of works by Allen Ginsberg] - preface, Brighton, [UK], 14 March 1971, (4 pages t.ms. (eighth draft; with changes in the author's hand) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George Landscape: 8 (poem), [London], [ca. Aug 1967], (1 page t.ms. (carbon copy) (Box 1)
    - Dowden, George Landscape: 9 (poem), [London], [ca. Aug 1967], (1 page t.ms. (carbon copy) (Box 1)
    - Ginsberg, Louis Speed (poem), [Paterson, NJ], [May 1967], (1 page t.ms. (with corrections) (Box 1)
      [For this item see Ginsberg, Louis. To George Dowden, 12 May 1967.]
    - Harding, Gumnar Poems: Green revolution, A new day, This was a few years after the war, Through the tunnel, Us, [Stockholm], [ca. Nov 1967], (5 t.ms. (carbon copies; translated by Anselm Hollo) (Box 1)
- Series II: Arranged Correspondence
  - A-L (Box 2)
  - M-Z (Box 3)
- Series III: A Bibliography of Works by Allen Ginsberg
  - Carbon transcripts (Box 4)
  - Drafts & notes (Box 4)
  - Working notes (Box 4)